<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Economic Indicators</title>
    <link>https://ecoindica.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Economic Indicators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:26:20 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ecoindica.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Trade</title>
      <link>https://ecoindica.com/posts/internationaltrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:26:20 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecoindica.com/posts/internationaltrade/</guid>
      <description>US International Trade International Trade time series plot. This graph shows US export and import from year 1929 to 2020.
Nepal International Trade International Trade time series plot. This graph shows export import from year 2000 to year 2020. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth and Recession</title>
      <link>https://ecoindica.com/posts/growthandrecession/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:25:51 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecoindica.com/posts/growthandrecession/</guid>
      <description>US Historical Growth and Recession The graph shows the US quarterly data on real GDP from 1947 to 2020. Shaded vertical bars represent recession or contraction. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ecoindica.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:06:36 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecoindica.com/about/</guid>
      <description>We would like to extend a warm welcome to our website, which has been developed by Yash Raj Lamsal, an assistant professor of economics at Kathmandu University. Our aim is to provide an exceptional learning experience to all students, educators, and individuals interested in understanding macroeconomic variables, their analysis, and data representation through visually appealing charts and graphs. Contact us at yashrajlamsal@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Components of Gross Domestic Product (GDP)</title>
      <link>https://ecoindica.com/posts/componentofgdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:06:36 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ecoindica.com/posts/componentofgdp/</guid>
      <description>The components of US Gross Domestic Product (GDP) GDP is divided into four parts: Consumption, Investment, Government Purchase, and Net Export. Net export is export minus import. These four parts are various forms of spending on domestically produced goods and services. The table shows the dollar value of components of the GDP and their percentage of the total. The table provides a percentage value of total for different components, where the share of import is subtracted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
